A Guide to the Ilona Nanasy Architectural Collection, 1978-2003
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Ilona Nanasy Architectural Collection 1978-2003
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2005-010
This collection has been added to the IAWA Small Collections (Ms2009-054). See the finding aid for that collection online.
4 oversize folders
Ilona Nanasy is an architect in Budapest, Hungary whose career began in 1978. The collection consists of information about residential, commercial, and competition projects.
Ilona Nanasy
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Ilona Nanasy Architectural Collection was donated to the International Archive of Women in Architecture at the Special Collections by its creator via Milka Bliznakov in 2003. Additional drawings were acquired the same way in 2005.
Biographical Information
Ilona Nanasay worked as the leading designer of public housing for the Hungarian Ministry of Housing from 1978-1991. In 1991, she opened her own architectural practice to design houses for private clients.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of architectural drawings and photographs of projects created by Ilona Nanasay between the years 1978-2003. There are black and white photocopies of plans for competition, residential, and commercial projects, most of which are in Budapest, Hungary. Some photographs show completed projects, while other images are computer generated and may be models of unbuilt projects. Most images are in color. Nanasay's curriculum vitae is also included in the collection. All materials are in Hungarian, and translations of the project names can be found on the reverse side of each project sheet.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in four folders, one containing her curriculum vitae, the other three holding her competition, residential, and commercial projects. The contents of each folder are arranged chronologically with undated material at the end.
Contents List
- Curriculum Vitae (Folder 10.1 (IAWA Small Collections, Ms2009-054))
- Competition Projects, 1978-2000, n.d. (Folder 10.2 (IAWA Small Collections, Ms2009-054))
  - Diploma Project, Education Center, 1978, (2 sheets)
  - Hotel Magnolia, 1979, (3 sheets)
  - Recreation Center, 1980, (3 sheets)
  - Hungarian Pavilion for the German International Exposition at Hannover, Germany, 2000, (6 sheets, 2 images)
  - Social Housing, Kethely, Hungary, (2 sheets)
  - Providencia Insurance Company, Budapest, (5 sheets)
  - National Theatre, Budapest, (1 image)
  - City Gate, Gyor, Hungary, (1 sheet)
- Commercial Projects, 1988-1993, n.d. (Folder 10.3 (IAWA Small Collections, Ms2009-054))
  - Technical School for Post Office Workers, Budapest, 1988, (2 sheets, 3 photos)
  - Office Building and Apartments on Podmaniczky Street, Budapest, 1989, (3 sheets, 2 images)
  - Council and Bank Office Building, Budapest, 1993, (2 sheets, 3 photos)
  - Health Center, Budapest, (1 sheet)
  - Shopping Center, Budapest, (2 images)
  - Duna Towers, Budapest, (1 image)
- Residential Projects, 1985-2003, n.d. (Folder 10.4 (IAWA Small Collections, Ms2009-054))
  - Housing for the Elderly, Budapest, 1980-85, (3 sheets, 1 image)
  - Village Housing Type, Hungary, 1989, (3 sheets, 2 images)
  - Residence, Budapest, 1997, (1 sheet, 2 images)
  - Guest House of the Department of the Interior, Budapest, 2001, (6 sheets, 6 images)
  - Residence, Nagytarcsa, Hungary, 2003, (1 image)
  - Residence, Leanyfalu, Hungary, 1993, (1 sheet, 1 image)